# **Thomas Seropian**

French nationality
Currently based in London, United Kingdom

thomas@seropian.io https://uk.linkedin.com/in/tseropian

## **Technical Lead / Senior Full Stack Engineer**

## Skillset

Managing web applications, leading technical team for an international online media publisher. Establishment and management of a team of 4 technologists in London for an international NGO.

Software engineering. Team recruitment and management. Agile delivery. Web applications design and development. System architecture, testing and hosting.

Leadership, communication with technical and non-technical audiences. Strong sense of innovation. Design and creation of user stories. Research, prototyping. Group training and capacity building. Creativity. Flexibility. Project management. Hiring, mentoring and performance management.

### Work experience

**Technical Lead (contract based)** for an international online media publishing group **Jamie Oliver,** London, United Kingdom – February to September 2017 (www.jamieoliver.com)

→ Responsible for infrastructure and web applications supporting Jamie's online presence.

Designing, defining roadmaps, scoping and delivering new features and APIs for jamieoliver.com and other departments of the business. Hands-on development of key features such as migrating CRM journey towards an API driven process. Integration with Salesforce.com. Developing SPAs. Managing legacy code base.

Managing AWS based infrastructure, including release processes, optimisations and improvements.

Leading technical team (both in house and freelancers), hiring, day to day management, code reviews and mentoring. Organising backlog and sprints. Maintaining technical documentation. Managing third party providers. Liaising with Internal stakeholders (project managers, product owners, business managers).

→ <u>Technology:</u> AWS (EC2, RDS, SQS, Elasticache, Route53, IAM, S3), PHP (MVC), Laravel, RESTful APIs, Redis, Solr, Javascript, Node.js, Angular, Vue.js, WordPress, Ansible, Linux, Apache, Nginx, Varnish, Vagrant

### Technology Manager for an international NGO

Internews London, United Kingdom – April 2015 to December 2016 (www.internews.org)

- → Leading the design, development and delivery of innovation and technology components

  Working with a multidisciplinary team supporting local media start-ups among the most repressive regimes.

  Leading on delivering full service of websites and news publishing apps from design to deployment and hosting. Hands-on control, testing and reviewing. Ensuring a security first approach. Prototyping.

  Managing and monitoring activities' budgets.
- ightarrow Managing technology team and resources across multiple projects (8 countries)

Overseeing recruitment and day-to-day managing a team of 4 technologists (2 developers, 1 coordinator and 1 helpdesk officer). Ensuring planning, coordination and distribution of work, setting priorities, agreeing detailed work plans, budgets and schedules. Coaching and mentoring team members. Performance management. Agile delivery. Responsible for technical architecture and roadmap. Strong focus on scalability, quality & security.

→ Strategic Development

Proposal planning and writing. Improving quality of development processes (including specification, operations, testing, deployment, policy writing...). Speaking at conferences and events

→ <u>Technology:</u> Wordpress, Drupal (7/8), Bootstrap, PHP MVC, Laravel, Javascript, HTML5, Node.js, WordPress, RESTful APIs, Cloud hosting (Public / Private), Ansible, Ubuntu, MySQL, Nginx, OpenVPN, GPG encryption

# Freelance Consultant in open source technologies

Self-Employed London, United Kingdom – April 2014 to September 2015 (www.seropian.io)

- $\rightarrow$  Designing & developing web applications and prototypes for various range of clients
- → Areas of work: Drupal, E-Commerce, intranet applications, Infrastructure management.

Designed and built a subscription-based application, including automated online payments. Agile Prototyping. Developed Intranet and extranet applications including import/export modules for a booking agent. Defined and prioritized user stories in close collaboration with different team members.

→ <u>Technology:</u> Drupal 7, Drush, Github, Selenium HQ, Vagrant, RESTful APIs

# ICT Projects Manager / Web Application Engineer for an international NGO Internews Europe Paris, France / London, United Kingdom - March 2009 to March 2014 (www.internews.eu)

→ On-line freedom of expression, support of local media, digital security

Designing, developing & supporting multilingual web applications, custom modules. Integration with social network (Twitter, Facebook) APIs. Writing documentation for users. Managing localizations, training & support

Writing user stories & specifications. Managing external contractors and developers, resources & infrastructures: Deployment and monitoring of servers, secure hosting & video platforms. Building, delivering and facilitating trainings & trainers on ICT topics. Training of trainers on website building and digital security (West Africa, MENA)

→ <u>Technology</u>: Drupal, Mediawiki, XML/JSON, PHP (OOP, MVC), MySQL, Solr, AWS, Collectd, Vagrant, Nginx

**Software Engineer** for a social networking service designed for a family use **Hellotipi.com** Paris, France – February 2008 to January 2009 (www.hellotipi.com)

 $\rightarrow$  Designed, developed and implemented new features for the service.

Video sharing. Photo tagging. Revamped registration process. Multilingual support. Managed client support.

→ <u>Technology</u>: Debian, Apache, MySQL, PHP5 (OOP, MVC), XML, Jquery, Ffmpeg.

#### ICT Projects Manager for a local NGO in Armenia

Fondation KASA Yerevan, Armenia - March 2006 to September 2007 (www.kasa.am)

Coordinated Computer trainings in youth training centres. Developed activities in 2 major cities.

Managed recruitment of local team. Provided technical support for training & social programs. Participated to feasibility studies & design for countrywide projects.

**Assistant Projects Manager** for e-training IT projects for an international training centre **Valeo Thermal Systems** Paris, France – March 2005 to February 2006 (www.valeo.com) Designed & implemented tools for course supports creation (virtual classes, e-learning modules).

## Education

### **MSc in Computer Sciences and Innovation**

Ecole Supérieure d'Informatique, Electronique, Automatique Paris, France

5 years engineering school in information technologies & electronics (www.esiea.fr).

 $\rightarrow$  Graduated with first class honours.

### **Foreign languages**

French: Mother tongue English: Fluent Spanish: Basic level Arabic: Beginner